Tiisetso Murray

Industrial Engineer and Web Developer

My BSc Engineering degree has equipped me to design, develop, test, and evaluate integrated systems for managing industrial production processes, including human work factors, quality control, inventory control, logistics and material flow, cost analysis, and production coordination.

During my university years, highlights were serving as class representative throughout the degree process, development of the university's first solar car, and tutoring underprivileged schoolchildren computer and life skills. Both were a chance to explore my love of design, engineering, and do work in the real world.

I then taught physics and chemistry at my high school (where I had been head prefect and part of a nationally successful eight man rowing team) before an assignment with a leading engineering company.

Consequently, I applied for a joint South Africa and Chinese Governments' scholarship which provided the opportunity to progress my interest in China. After reaching a level of intermediate conversational Mandarin and a deepened understanding of Chinese culture. I continued my stay in China with a MSc in manufacturing followed by a two semester exchange in Milan, Italy. Finally, returning I am to Beijing to write my thesis.

I am interested in researching real world problems where advancements will improve lives. I am passionate about nutrition and a "prevention is better than cure" approach to global obesity and metabolic syndrome related diseases. I am fascinated with tech and innovation in agriculture and mobility. I am also interested in how technology integrates into our everyday lives for better and worse and in leveraging existing platforms to extract benefits.

EDUCATION

BSc Engineering (Industrial)

University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg

Feb 2009 to Dec 2012

Postgraduate Computer Science

University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg

Feb 2013 to Feb 2014

Mandarin Language Program

Tsinghua University, Beijing

Sep 2016 to Jul 2017

MSc Global Manufacturing

Tsinghua University, Beijing

Sep 2017 to Mar 2020

MSc Management Engineering

Politecnico Di Milano, Milan

Sep 2018 to Jul 2019

EXPERIENCE

WeChat: tiisetso26

Industrial Engineer — VescoPlastics

Mar 2016 to Sep 2017 - Johannesburg

Email: tiisetsomurray@gmail.com Passport: Republic of South Africa

Worked on process improvement and business development at an advanced low friction polymer bearing manufacturer. Analysed and improved inventory control, factory layout, material flow, and production processes. Implemented network monitoring technologies, setup Google Business and Adwords campaigns, and revamped company website and email backends.

- Planned major factory layout improvement.
- Reduced network downtime, improved speed and increased reliability of company website and email.
- Resolved bottlenecks and inefficiencies in production and office processes.

Science Teacher — Parktown Boys' High School

Oct 2015 to Aug 2016 - Johannesburg

Taught physics and chemistry to all grades at a top public high school. Designed and conducted new experiments and demonstrations to stimulate interest in STEM disciplines.

SKILLS

Software

Spreadsheet

Microsoft Excel, Apple Numbers

Software and Web Development

Java, Python, HTML+CSS(Bootstrap, Semantic UI), Javascript, React.js. Node.js.

CAD Software

Autodesk Inventor, Solid Edge, Fusion 360

Presentations

Microsoft Powerpoint, Apple Keynote

Languages

English - Native

Mandarin - Intermediate

AWARDS

Italian Government MAECI - Scholarship, 2018

Chinese Scholarship Council - Scholarship, 2017

Chinese Scholarship Council - Scholarship, 2016

MIT GSL - Winner and Best Entrepreneur, 2013

Plastics SA Design Competition – Winner, 2012

Allan Gray Orbis Foundation - Fellowship, 2010

Engineering Drawing - Certificate of Merit, 2009